So, in this video we're going to have an introduction to Xcode on the Mac,
En este video vamos a introducir Xcode en Mac
and by the end of it, you'll be able to compile simple
al final podras compilar codigo simple
C++ code and prove that your system is working. So, let's dive
de C++ y probar que tu sistema funciona. Empecemos
straight in! OK, so over here on my
directamente! Ok, aqui en mi
Mac, Xcode has finished downloading. There you go! It's got a proper icon
Mac, Xcode ha acabado de descargar. Tiene su propio icono.
and thing, so I'm going to open it. Another way to open that, of course, is to
Voy a abrirlo. Otra manera de abrirlo es yendo a Spotlight,
go to Spotlight, which you can go Command and Space and then type Xcode.
con Command y espacio, tecleando Xcode
So, Xcode opens! Now, you may get a starting screen like
Cuando abra, puede que veas una pantalla inicial como esta
this. If you've used Xcode before, then you might
Si has usado Xcode antes puede que tengas
have a lot of windows open. You can check your Windows Menu, if you do. Just close all those
muchas ventanas abiertas. Si miras el menú de ventanas cierra todas.
windows, and let's just create a new Xcode project.
Creamos un nuevo proyecto de Xcode.
The other way you can do that is File and New and then
Otra manera es archivo, new y proyecto.
Project. So, what type are we going to have to use to use C++?
¿Que tipo vamos a usar con C++?
Well, depending on the type you use here, you may or may not get access to C++,
Dependiendo del tipo que uses aquí puede que tengas acceso o no a C++,
so we're going to make an OS X application and
hacemos una aplicación OS X y
again a Command Line Tool. I say again, because that's what I just did with
y de nuevo una herramienta de línea de comandos. Digo de nuevo porque
the PC people in the previous video. So, I want you to choose OS X,
hice lo mismo antes en PC. Voy a escoger OS X.
Application, Command Line Tool, and then, Next. Let's just call this Hello
aplicación , herramienta de línea de comandos, lo llamamos Hello World
World. Now, the important thing is that you have a
Es importante que tengas una ayuda para
Organization Identifier. Put something in there. I'm putting in Embrace IT,
organizarte. Pon algo aqui, yo pongo Embrace IT
and the language is set to C++.
con el lenguaje C++.
OK, so settings something like this. The only one that actually matters
Opciones algo asi. La unica que importa es
is C++. Then, where are we going to save that?
C++. ¿Donde vamos a guardar eso?
Well, I'm going to save that into this Downloads Folder,
Lo guardamos en la carpeta de descargas
replacing what I've already got.
sustituyendo lo que tengo ya.
And here we go! Now, we're in Xcode. Lots of new stuff going on,
Y estamos en Xcode. Muchas cosas en
on the screen. So, you have a View Menu. If you find that you don't have
la pantalla. Tienes un menú Vistas. Si lo encuentras no tienes
any of the pains that I'm looking at, then you can come into this View Menu and
ninguno de los problemas que estoy viendo, puedes ir a este menú de vistas y
you can choose say Show Standard Editor. Standard
eliges mostrar editor estandard.
Editor, Show Standard Editor, and then that will allow you to come back to
Editor mostrar editor estandard, y entonces esto te permitira volver a
a layout, something like this. But what we're looking for, on the left-hand side
una disposición, algo asi. Pero lo que buscamos a la izquierda
in this bit here, which is showing all the files of the solution,
aquí, que muestra todos los archivos de la solución,
is main.cpp. So, double click that and it'll
es main.cpp. Doble click y
pop-up in a separate window. Well, if you don't want a separate window you can just
saldrá en una ventana distinta. Si no la quieras puedes clickearla y saldra aqui
click on it and it'll come up here. As long as you can see the code, it doesn't matter!
clickea y saldra aqui. Lo que importa es que veas el código.
Now, let's briefly overview what we can see. The green things are comments, so this is
Veamos ahora, lo que tenemos aqui. Lo verde son comentarios, el ordenador
ignored by the computer. This is just for you. Xcode automatically
los ignora . Son para ti. Xcode nos pone automaticamente
puts all this stuff in for us. And then, we have a #include
esto. Después, tenemos #include
here. It's a little bit different to what he PC guys saw
&lt;iostream&gt; aqui. Es un poco distinto a lo que tenemos en PC
in Visual Studio. They had to add this line or set this
con Visual Studio. Tenían que añadir esta linea o configurarlos
themselves, but in this case, Xcode is including it. Now, what a
ellos, pero Xcode lo incluye.
#include does it is, it gives your code access to other code, and what it's giving us
#include te da acceso de código a otro código, en este caso
access to, in this case, is something call an  or input output stream. And that's
a algo llamado &lt;iostream&gt; o transmission input output
going to allow us to write out to the
nos permitira escribir a la consola
Console. And what I want you to do is, just find this
Ahora, encuentra
main function here, and then,
main function y
between return and the comment that is automatically there, I want you to write this
entre return y los comentarios que están aquí, escribamos esta línea
line. And I'll re-write it for you. std::
la escribire std::
so that is looking inside the standard, what we call
está dentro del standard lo que llamamos
name space. A name space is a gathering of methods that you can call upon.
name space.  Name space es un conjunto de métodos que puedes y usar
cout, which is short for character
cout, abreviación de carácter
output, and then, you need a double back chevron like that. And then,
output, y después necesitas dos menor signos <<
you need to say "Hello World. And we need to do a backslash n to represent
tienes que decir Hello World. Y hacemos \n para representar una
new line. Notice how Xcode automatically is closing your
nueva linea. Fijate como Xcode nos cierra las comillas
quotes for you, and then, a semi-colon on the end. So, that's
después un punto y coma al final
the line you need! And then, we simply go up here!
eso es todo. Después vamos aquí arriba
Product, Run!
product, Run!
Now, that's going to Build Succeeded! With any luck, if it doesn't, then you've written something slightly
esto hace un Build con éxito. Sino lo consigue, has escrito algo un poco
different to this, so just check it character by character.
cambiado, revisalo letra a letra.
And down here, in the output... If you can't see the output then you can
Aquí en el output, si no lo puedes ver activalo
toggle it up, View, and then Debug Area, and
View, Debug Area y
Activate Console or Shift, Command, and C.
activa consola o mayúscula, command y C.
And that'll bring the Console up here, and we can see Hello World. And then the
Esto traerá la Consola aquí, y podemos decir Hello World. Y el programa termina con
program ended with exit code: 0. Perfect! So, this proves that
código de salida: 0. ¡Perfecto! Esto prueba que
Xcode can compile your code. Now, compiling means taking
Xcode puede compilar su código. Compilar significa tomar este código
this code, that we will learn to read through the course of the course...
que aprenderemos a leer en el transcurso del curso.
You're not just going to be following me writing code. All of this is going to be explained carefully
No vas a copiar lo que hago siempre a lo largo del curso. Todo va a estar explicado
as we go through. But it takes this stuff, this text, and it turns it into a format
conforme se haga. Pero coge este texto, y lo convierte  a un formato que
the computer can actually run. So congratulations! You've just written a
el ordenador pueda ejecutar. ¡Felicidades! Acabas de escribir
ridiculously basic C++ program, but it does prove you've your
un programa básico en C++, pero demuestra que tu ambiente está configurado y
environment all setup and ready. And that means that, when in the next video,
listo. Significa que en el siguiente video vamos a Unreal Engine
we go into Unreal Engine it's going to be happy, because it'll have
y va a estar bien porque
a C++ compilation pathway that it can use to
tendrá un modo de compilar C++
actually build games. So well done, and I'll see you
que podemos usar para hacer juegos. BIen hecho y nos vemos
in the next video!
en el siguiente video